残酷な天使のように 少年よ 神話になれ
青い風が今 胸のドアを叩いても
私だけをただ見つめて 微笑んでるあなた
そっと触れるもの 求めることに夢中で
運命さえ まだ知らない 痛いけな瞳
だけどいつか気づくでしょう その背中には
遥か未来 目指すための羽があること
残酷な天使の手勢 窓辺から
やがて飛び立つ 吹き飛ばしる熱いパトスで
思い出を裏切るなら この空を抱いて輝く
何故?
お前は一目 悩んだ moments
前後な天使 της
Ashino Lakes 2 and 3.
I hope we won't have many more holes to fill.
Which reminds me, Chairman Keele came to see me yesterday.
He was complaining about the delays.
He was pretty steamed.
He even hinted at your dismissal.
Adam is going well.
And work on the dummy plug for the Ava project is proceeding.
What are the old men at Zaylay complaining about now?
The fact that the instrumentality project is behind schedule?
The projects are all linked together. There are no problems.
Including Rey?
Well, I won't impress you.
So how will we deal with you-know-who?
Let him do as he wishes. The same with the Marduk Institute.
I agree. We can make use of him. For a while.
What started here?
Sixteen years ago.
It's me.
Ah, so it is.
This is Shannon Bio Inc., a foreign chemical firm.
It's been like this for nine years.
Nine years without a single change.
So far, 106 corporations out of the 108 affiliated with the Marduk Institute have turned out to be dummy companies.
And this one is the 107th.
This is the company's registration record.
And you want me to take a look at the board of directors, don't you?
You already know about this?
I know most of the names.
Yes.
The Marduk Institute is supposed to be an advisory body established under the control of the Human Instrumentality Committee for the purpose of selecting Ava pilots.
Something's not adding up right here.
Your task is to investigate the nerve.
Getting involved with the Marduk may be an ill-advised step.
Well, I can't help it.
My nose for trouble has a penchant for getting my eyes in the wrong places.
Hi, this is Kaji.
I'm out right now, but you can leave your name and a message at the beep.
Help me, Kaji!
Don't touch me, you pervert!
That ought to do it.
What's going on?
I was just calling Kaji.
I wanted him to take me out tomorrow.
I've been calling him and calling him, but he's always out these days.
He's always out doing something.
You mean you'll be available tomorrow?
Unfortunately, it seems so.
Great!
Then I've got a favor to ask you.
Huh?
Well, you see...
What?
A date?
The guy's a friend of Kadama, my big sister, and he keeps asking and asking me to set you and him up.
Pretty please!
Huh?
Get back to your work!
Sorry!
Why don't you get back to work, Toji?
Don't care!
Microsis operation completed.
Inversible graph measurement finalized.
Oh, which dress are you wearing?
Oh, for the wedding tomorrow?
Well, I wore the pink suit for Kiyomi's wedding, and I wore the dark blue dress for Kotoko's shower, and...
There's that orange one.
You haven't worn that one lately.
The orange one?
Well, there's a reason I haven't worn it.
It's too tight.
Ah, thank you!
Maybe I should just buy a new one.
Man, all these stupid weddings are killing my bank account.
Tell me about it.
We've been to so many showers, I'm almost broke.
Yeah, it's like everyone's in a rush to get married before they turn 30.
And you don't want to be the last one still single, do you?
Excuse me?
Okay, you guys can take off now.
Good work.
It's about time!
These stupid experiments are really getting on my nerves!
Speaking of which, Shinji seems more subdued than usual.
Tomorrow's the day.
Oh, yeah.
Tomorrow.
I have to see my father tomorrow.
What should I talk to him about, Ray?
I don't understand.
Why are you asking me?
Because I've seen you talking with my father and actually enjoying it.
Say, my father, what's he like?
I don't know.
Oh.
Have you been watching me because you wanted to ask that question?
Mm-hmm.
Hey, when we were cleaning, that cloth, the way you ringed it, it reminded me of a mother when you squeezed it.
A mother?
Uh, yeah.
It just reminded me of a mom.
I bet you'll make a great mother, Ray.
I mean, you embarrass me.
I'm home.
What's happening?
You better go to bed, Oscar.
Don't you have a date tomorrow?
With some med student.
Oh, Misato!
Can I use your lavender perfume?
Uh, no.
No, Nini.
That stuff's not for kids.
Is Shinji in his room?
Yeah, ever since he got home.
I don't think he wants to meet his father.
If he hates him so much, why doesn't he just say?
You Japanese are weird.
Well, he doesn't actually hate him.
That's the problem.
Leave.
Good work, Shinji.
Shinji!
I'm coming in, okay?
You're worried about seeing your father tomorrow, right?
You mustn't run away, Shinji.
Nothing will ever change unless you have the courage to step forward.
I know that, Misato.
You're going to find out the truth.
You've got to keep moving forward.
After each step, you've got to keep taking another afterwards.
Anyway, when you see him tomorrow, you've got to keep your chin held high.
Because you'll be seeing her, too.
Good night, Shinji.
You bought a new dress, didn't you?
Let me see.
Oh, you want to see it, do you?
It's an expensive one.
Price doesn't always be flexible.
Tell me about it.
Well, what do you think?
Did you pick that one with Paji in mind?
Grow up.
It was a long time ago.
Well, see ya.
Later.
Aw.
You must keep three bags in your heart.
And now, let us proceed to the reception.
Little boy Blue is late.
That oversexed idiot's never been on time in his whole lazy life.
For your dates, you mean?
He gets to work early.
Hello, girls.
You're looking particularly lovely today.
I had a little trouble getting out of work on time.
I find that hard to believe since you don't do anything.
You could at least have taken the time and trouble to shave that awful stubble.
Your tie is crooked.
Well, thank you.
You act like you're married.
You're very astute, Ritsipoo.
Who'd marry this bomb?
It's been three years since we were last here.
That's when I ran away.
I haven't come back here since then.
I just don't believe that my mom is really resting here.
I don't even remember her face.
Burying memories is man's way of surviving.
But there are some things a man should never forget.
Yui taught me that one irreplaceable thing, Shinji.
That is the reason I come here, to confirm that commitment.
You don't have a picture of her?
No photographs.
Even this grave is an artifice.
Nothing remains.
That's like my teacher said.
You cast everything away.
Everything is kept in my heart.
I'm satisfied with that.
Our time is up.
I'm leaving now.
Father!
I'm glad that we could talk together today.
Indeed.
I'm leaving now.
I'm sorry.
What?
That was very nice, Shinji.
I didn't know you played.
I started when I was five, but I'm still not very good.
I have no talent at all.
Well, perseverance wins the battle.
I'm impressed.
I only started because my teachers told me to,
but I could have quit any time.
So why didn't you?
Huh? Nobody told me to stop, I guess.
Oh, I should have known.
Hey, you're back early.
I thought you were going out to dinner, too.
Oh, my date was even more boring than you.
So while he was standing in line for the roller coaster,
I took a train back here.
That seems kind of cold.
Oh, gosh, he's the only real man in my life.
I know it's getting a little late,
but I've got to go powder my nose.
Making a quick exit?
High heels.
It's been a while since we went out together.
She's drinking too much.
She's losing her control.
Sometimes you just have to drink to keep yourself under control.
All of us do.
Well, you did used to live with her,
so I guess you'd know the truth.
Well, that was a lifetime ago.
She didn't even own a set of heels back then.
That's not how we saw it back when we were in school.
We were kids, Ritsu.
That wasn't real.
We were just children playing house.
It was nice.
But life's not that simple.
Oh, I almost forgot.
The cat dragged this in.
Thank you, Kaji, for being honest.
To the ladies, yes.
Otherwise, eh...
I doubt that.
And Misato?
I've lost that war before.
Doom battles aren't my style.
I think you still have a chance.
Well, what about you?
Oh, I don't like to talk about myself.
There's nothing much to say.
Why is she taking so long?
How much makeup can she wear?
Hmm.
What were you doing in Kyoto?
I wasn't in Kyoto.
Don't try to fool me.
You'll get your fingers burned if you get too involved in this.
That's the advice of a friend.
I'd rather be burned by the heat of my passion for you.
Well, should I buy you some fireworks, then?
Hello.
Oh, you never change, do you?
Of course I change.
The act of living is an embracement of change.
Homeostasis and transestasis.
Homeo-what?
One is a force to maintain the present status,
and the other is a force for constant change.
Anything that lives is composed of these two conflicting forces.
Like men and women.
I'll just be taking off now.
I've got some work to do.
Now?
That's too bad.
Have fun.
But...
Hey, Shinji, it's me.
I'm going to be out drinking with Kaji.
Don't wait up for me, okay?
Right.
Yeah, sure.
Hmm, Misato?
Yeah, she'll be late, so don't wait up for her.
What?
You mean she won't be back until tomorrow morning?
I doubt it.
She's going out with Kaji.
Are you dense?
That guarantees it.
Drinking till you throw up.
How old are you?
Old enough to regret it.
I'm old enough as well.
You're damn right.
I can't believe that you wear high heels these days.
Time really does fly.
You need to shave your sloppy face.
Okay, let me walk.
Thank you.
Kaji, do you think I've changed?
You're even prettier.
It's not what I mean.
When I told you there was someone else, it wasn't true.
But you knew that, didn't you?
No.
One morning, I just realized how much like my father you were.
I panicked.
I couldn't believe that I wanted a man just like my father.
I was terrified.
So I ran.
I was so scared.
I was afraid of becoming a woman.
Afraid of being with you.
And thought I hated my father.
But then I fell in love with a man who was just like my father.
I thought joining Nerve would be a way to sever those ties.
And then it turned out that my father was with Nerve.
So I tried to bury all of my feelings by swearing to avenge myself against the angels.
Choosing that path was your decision.
You don't have to apologize to anyone.
Don't bullshit me, Kaji.
I just turned tail and ran.
It was just an escape from the real world and my father.
I'm no better than Shinji is.
I'm a coward, Kaji.
Well, it's just like right now.
I had to get up the nerve to get drunk enough to even tell you the truth.
I'm a child.
I have no right to be Shinji's guardian.
Enough!
Look at me, afraid to accept a helping hand up from a man,
except when I'm so falling down drunk that I don't even know what I'm doing.
I'm a horrible woman and I'd use you.
Use you.
Cut it out!
Because I'm a coward.
I'm pathetic.
Hey, Shinji, you want to kiss me?
Huh?
What?
Kissing.
You know, have you ever done it?
Uh-uh.
So let's do it.
But why?
I've got nothing else to do.
That's your reason?
You're weird.
Afraid to kiss a girl on the anniversary of your mom's death?
Is she watching you from up in heaven?
That's not it.
Or are you scared?
I'm not afraid.
Pucker up.
Right.
Did you brush your teeth?
Yeah.
Then here I come.
Um...
Stop breathing.
It's tickling me.
Oh...
Wait...
Ugh.
Ah!
Huh?
Ah, I...
I should never kiss a kill time.
Hang on. We're here.
Hey, Kaji.
What? Hey! Hello, Kaji!
There. I'll be leaving now.
You can spend the night here.
I'd never live it down if I went to work like this.
Oh, you could do it!
Hey, come on, Kaji. It'd...
Later, Asuka.
Lavender.
Take care of Misato, okay?
Sure.
Good night, Kaji.
Yeah.
What's wrong? You look upset.
That's because you kissed me, you jerk!
Let me call a roll.
Ladies first.
Ayanami?
Rei Ayanami?
Is she absent again?
Oh, boy.
Oh, my God.
Oh.
Hi. Feeling better this morning, are we?
I'm sober now, thank you.
I'm glad to hear that.
Is this your real profession, Kaji?
Or something you just do part-time?
What do you think?
It would seem to me that there must be at least two Ryoji Kajis here.
One works for Nerve's special inspections,
and the other would appear to be a spy for the Japanese government.
So you knew.
Don't underestimate Nerve.
Was this ordered by Ikari?
No, my initiative.
But if you stay with this other job, you'll die.
Perhaps not.
Commander Ikari is using me for his own ends.
But I am sorry that I've kept this secret from you.
I'll let it pass.
Repayment for your help yesterday.
I appreciate that.
But you should know that the Commander and Ritsuko are hiding something from you too.
And this is it!
Oh, my God.
Is it an Eva?
No, it can't be.
Yes.
The key to the second impact and everything that's happened since.
The starting point of everything.
This is Adam.
Adam?
But why is the first angel here?
You're right, Kaji.
I don't know Nerve.
I don't know Nerve at all.
Viewer.
I don't know Nerve.
But why is the name of Candy?
This is easy.
In other words, hold my hand
In other words, darling, kiss me
Fill my heart with song
And let me sing forevermore
You are all I long
For all I worship and I do
In other words, please be true
In other words, I love you
After finally getting ahead of Asuka in the sync test
Shinji is full of pride
But everything comes crashing down
When he's swallowed by the sea of Dirac
As his Ava's energy supply runs out
Fear and loneliness surround him
Enveloping him in a new level of anguish and despair
His very survival is at stake in the next thrilling episode